Alfredo Alcalá

IT Support and Application Specialist

With+12 years in the technology area, I am characterized by being a person focused on continuing to obtain knowledge in order to generate a greater contribution to my projects. Skills include networking, security, analytical thinking, and creative problem-solving. Able to apply customer service concepts to IT to improve the user experience for customers, employees, and management.



alfredoalcala.h@gmail.com

+57 319 392 7070

Bogota, Colombia

alfredoalcala.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/alfredo-alcala-h

in

EXPERIENCE

Senior IT Support Specialist

Huge Inc

04/2022 - Present

IT Support Specialist

Huge Inc

03/2021 - Present

Functions

- Provision and deploy Mac systems for end users (MDM, DEP)
- Perform research and collaboration with other IT staff to resolve issues
- Troubleshoot and resolve software issues (Adobe Suite, Google Apps, MS Office etc.)
- Provide remote support using various tools (Team Viewer, ARD, Casper Remote)
- Manage users, groups and email lists via Windows Active Directory
- Resolve end user network issues (File shares, DNS, VPN. printers, etc.)

Application Specialist

Netcom Wireless SA

10/2017 - 12/2020

Functions

- Coordinate with senior-level analysts and assist end-users and stakeholders to resolve and layout required information infrastructure.
- Develop, implement and optimize stored procedures and functions using T-SQL.
- Suggest new queries. Analyze existing SQL queries for performance improvements.
- Collaborate with developers and vendors to secure infrastructure being developed for end-user needs and ensure achievement of all business objectives.
- Assist with system check and quality assurance. Work with aid end users and provide support to infrastructure facilities and ensure smooth adoption.
- Administer application and provide technical expertise in development and execution of all IT systems.
- Verifying the security of third-party vendors and collaborating with them to meet security requirements

SKILLS

Coding(Python)/Scripting(PowerShell)	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Server Management (IIS/ AD/SSRS/WDS)	• • • • •
Cloud (AWS/Azure/GCP)	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Databases SQL/ NO-SQL	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
CyberSec/Ethical Hacking	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
MacOS(MDM/DEP)/Linux	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Networking(OSI Model)	• • • • •
Analytics	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
SAAS	• • • • •

EDUCATION

Associate's degree in Informatics

University institute of industrial technology Rodolfo Loero Arismendi

2007 - 2011

CERTIFICATES

IBM CyberSecurity Analyst

Google IT Support

Open Source Software Development, Linux and Git The linux Foundation

JavaScript, JQuery and JSON University of Michigan

Introduction to Data Analitics for Bussines

University of Colorado Boulder